<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tech{know}logy blog</title>
    <description>techknowlogy club&#39;s blog</description>
    <link>http://techknowlogy.github.io//wlog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://techknowlogy.github.io//wlog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 19:22:09 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 19:22:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thought Experiments and a Goodbye Before the Vacation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Date: Apr 27, 2015, Wednesday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place: IT Lab 6, ASE, Coimbatore&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plan for the session: To introduce the different levels of thought and work between the inception of an idea and it’s implementation, and to familiarise attendees with the computational thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools/programs planned to use: Heavy usage of the Python programming language for demonstrations, a couple of programs to demonstrate linking between thoughts and solutions on paper to those on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem: People who are generally afraid of programming and otherwise active in terms of visualising ideas and thoughts are afraid so because of a divide between the way they think naturally and the way the need to understand how a computer thinks[?]. A significant portion of beginners are taught programming with an emphasis on the syntactical working of a particular language. Due importance which must be given to the logical constructs and thought patterns is often found lacking. The aim of this session was to try and identify such symptoms and help have fun while thinking of ideas and programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming is not the goal, it can be an effective means to reach your goal, provided you learn to use your tools well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get to work:
Problem 1: A basic problem involving using the built-in os module in python. The program involved reorganising files in a directory by renaming them according to some predefined rules. [Courtesy Udacity’s course on Introductory Programming in Python for the idea]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start with, let’s say I have a message for you. The message is in the form of photos (.jpg files) inside a directory, each photo carrying one letter, or a space, or a period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that the photos in the directory are sorted by filenames. So, I’ve named all my files in the msg directory after names of cities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to make things not so easy, I’ve scrambled the letters in the message by altering the filenames. Each filename has a random number prefix in front of the name of a city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/techknowlogy/techknowlogy.github.io/blob/master/master/2015-05-03/before_exec.png&quot; alt=&quot;Before execution of the program&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The task in this problem was to rename all the files in a way that the random number prefixes are filtered, and the result is that the letters of the message are arranged in the order which was intended earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/techknowlogy/techknowlogy.github.io/blob/master/master/2015-05-03/after_exec.png&quot; alt=&quot;After execution of the program&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No big funda here. The main purpose of the program was to get you acquainted with certain important functions and the program flow in python. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 01:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://techknowlogy.github.io//wlog/activities/2015/05/04/thought-experiments-and-a-goodbye-before-the-vacation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://techknowlogy.github.io//wlog/activities/2015/05/04/thought-experiments-and-a-goodbye-before-the-vacation.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>activities</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re proud to announce the tech{know}logy club’s blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it co-incidental that Sarup’s current cow says the following fortune?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;

[sarupbanskota@banas wlog]$ fortune | cowsay
 ______________________________________ 
/ Did you know ...                     \
|                                      |
\ That no-one ever reads these things? /
 -------------------------------------- 
        \   ^__^
         \  (oo)\_______
            (__)\       )\/\
                ||----w |
                ||     ||

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prove us wrong :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 09:04:06 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://techknowlogy.github.io//wlog/announcement/2014/10/04/helloworld.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://techknowlogy.github.io//wlog/announcement/2014/10/04/helloworld.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
